drfuhrman.com 2019-03-01

# Privacy Policy | DrFuhrman.com

_Latest Updated: August 29, 2018_

## Introduction

DrFuhrman.com respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. The following Privacy Policy (the or this “Policy”) describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website, DrFuhrman.com (our “Website”) and/or our App Nutrient IQ (our “App”), and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information, as well as how you can control our use of it.

This Policy applies to information we collect including but not limited to:

  * On this Website;
  * On our App;
  * Through your communication with our Customer Service team;
  * Through your communication or posts on our Member Forums;
  * Through recipe submissions;
  * Through recipe comments;
  * Through Success Stories
  * Through the health tracker;
  * Through blog comments;
  * Through your communication or posts in our member webinars; and
  * In e-mail, text and other electronic messages between you and this Website or App.

This policy does not apply to information collected by:

  * Us offline, including at Dr. Fuhrman events; and
  * Any third party, including our subsidiaries, affiliates and Fuhrman Affiliate Program, through any application, content, or advertising that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website or App.

Please read this Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.

## Who may not use this site

### Children under the age of 18:

Neither our Website nor App is intended or designed to attract children under 18 years of age. No one under age 18 may make purchases, use any of the interactive comment features of this Website or App, or provide any personal information, including but not limited to name, email address, physical address, or birth date. If you believe that a child under 18 is using our Website or App, please contact us by one of the methods listed in the “Contact Us” section below.

## Information we collect and how we use it

### Information we collect:

We may collect personally identifiable information about you, including but not limited to your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, birth date, IP address, and credit card or bank account number. We may also collect sensitive information, such as physical, health, and/or diet information, necessary for us to provide our service to you. Additionally, we may collect information including the type of browser you used to access the Website, the time and date you accessed it, and the pages you accessed during your visit.

We collect this information in a variety of ways, including but not limited to when you:

  * Visit the Website
  * Visit the App
  * Purchase, order, return, exchange, or request certain information about our products and services;
  * Sign up for a membership;
  * Subscribe to receive our newsletters or emails;
  * Attend a member webinar;
  * Post content in our Member Forum or elsewhere on the Website or App;
  * Contact our customer service team;
  * Enter into a contest, sweepstake, or respond to a survey;
  * Provide us with comments or suggestions; or
  * Share our Website or App contents with others via email or social media using our “share” capabilities.

We promise that we do not sell any of your personal information to third parties.

### Cookies, Tracers, Log Files and Tracking Technology:

Our Website utilizes “cookies.” A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. It allows us to recognize you when you return to the Website, provide us with information to personalize our Website in accordance with your preferences, and improve the overall performance of our Website. You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. You may also decide not to receive cookies from this Website (see additional information in the “Opt-Out” section below).

We may also utilize “tracers,” “web beacons,” and “log files” to determine which pages you visit, what browser you used to access our Website, the date and time you accessed it, the number of clicks, and other related website statistics on an individual user and aggregate level.

Any usage tracking is for internal use only for further development of DrFuhrman.com.

The Company may also collect information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the Website, the areas or pages of the Website that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing the Website, the number of times you return to the Website and other click-stream data. This helps us assist you by allowing us to understand how visitors use our Website. This data also becomes part of your unique profile and allows us to make your shopping experience beneficial. We, or a third party designated by us (such as Google Analytics), may also collect information from your activities on the Website as well as other sites for the purpose of providing advertisements and other content that is customized to your interests and preferences.

## How we use your information

We may use your personal information in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. We may use the personal information we obtain about you to:

  * process and fulfill orders and purchases via this Website or App and keep you informed about the status of your order;
  * operate, administer, evaluate, develop, manage and improve our business and the online services (including operating, administering, analyzing and improving our products, and services; developing new products and services; managing and evaluating the effectiveness of our communications; performing accounting, auditing, billing reconciliation and collection activities and other internal functions);
  * establish and manage your online account;
  * identify and authenticate you so you may order our products/services and access and use the relevant online services;
  * provide customer and technical support and respond to inquiries;
  * upload user content that may include your personal information;
  * communicate with you by email, telephone, postal mail or through other methods regarding news updates, notices, special promotional offers, advertisements and marketing materials, our products and services, or other information which may be of interest to you;
  * communicate about, and administer participation in, special events, programs, promotions, offers, surveys, focus groups and market research;
  * perform data analytics (including market research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization and aggregation of personal information);
  * manage career opportunities, including for recruitment purposes, employee onboarding and other Human Resources purposes;
  * increase and maintain the safety and security of our products and the online services and prevent misuse;
  * notify you about product safety and recall information, such as reporting adverse event, communicating product recall;
  * protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities; and
  * comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements and relevant industry standards and policies.
  * We also may use the information we collect about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection and obtain your consent if required by applicable law.
  * If you wish to opt-out of receiving promotional communications from us at any time, simply follow the instructions described in the "Opt-Out" section below in this Privacy Policy.

We may link or combine your personal information with other information (such as transaction history) that is available from our records and other sources. We may use this combined information for purposes such as marketing and advertising programs; to enforce the online services’ policies; to protect the online services, our customers and others; to comply with applicable law; and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

## Protection of your information

### Security of your personal information:

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of your personal information in our custody and control. We also are committed to employing commercially reasonable procedures and technology in order to protect the security of our Website or our App.

Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or use your personal information for improper purposes.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. If you are a member or where you have chosen a password for access to certain parts of our Website or App, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We also urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website or App. The Member Forums, while part of a "Member-only" community, are message boards that become accessible and public once you post your messages. The information you share may be viewed by other users of the Website or App, and may result in unwanted e-mail or contacts from third parties.

Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk and DrFuhrman.com is not responsible.

### Secure Shopping:

When you place orders on our Website or App, all of your order information, including your card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the Internet using 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology. Additionally, only employees who need your personal information to perform a specific job (e.g., customer service representative) are granted access to this information.

You may be able to create an account on our Website or App with a username and password. We recommend you exercise extreme care in protecting your password information and do not publicly share any of your passwords. You are responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your account password, and you are responsible for any access to or use of the Site by you or another person or entity using your password, whether or not such access or use has been authorized by or on behalf of you.

ALTHOUGH WE WILL TAKE (AND REQUIRE OUR THIRD-PARTY PROVIDERS TO TAKE) REASONABLE SECURITY PRECAUTIONS TO PROTECT THE PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM AND STORED ON THE SITE, BECAUSE OF THE OPEN NATURE OF THE INTERNET, WE CANNOT GUARANTEE THAT PERSONAL INFORMATION STORED ON OUR SERVERS, TRANSMITTED TO OR FROM A USER, OR OTHERWISE IN OUR CARE WILL BE ABSOLUTELY SAFE FROM INTRUSION BY OTHERS, SUCH AS HACKERS. ACCORDINGLY, WE DISCLAIM ANY LIABILITY FOR ANY THEFT OR LOSS OF, UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS OR DAMAGE TO, OR INTERCEPTION OF ANY DATA OR COMMUNICATIONS.

### Third party affiliates, links, and advertising:

Our Website and App may contain advertising for or links to our affiliates, business partners, or other third parties. Please refer to the individual policies of any links and affiliates found on the Website or App as they may have different collection, protection, and disclosure procedures from those contained in this Policy. DrFuhrman.com is not responsible for the content or for the policies of these third party websites.

## Disclosure of your information

We may disclose information that does not identify any individual without restriction. We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide us with as follows:

  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, if you give us an e-mail address to share content from the Website or App with another person, we will transmit the content of that e-mail and your e-mail address to that recipient;
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information;
  * With your consent;
  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates;
  * To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business, and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them;
  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process or to respond to any government or regulatory request;
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of DrFuhrman.com, our customers, or others; and
  * To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of DrFuhrman.com assets

## Choices about how we use and disclose your information

### Information disclosure and correction requests:

You may request access to the personal information that we have about you. If you are a registered user or member, you can review and change your personal information by logging into the Website or App and visiting your account profile page. You may also contact us (see “Contact Us” section below) to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.

If you delete your User Contributions, as defined in the Terms of Use, from the Website or App, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Website or App users. Proper access and use of information provided on the Website of App, including User Contributions, is governed by our Terms of Use.

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, once per calendar year. To make such a request, please contact us using one of the methods listed in the “Contact Us” section below.

## Opt-Out

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this Website or App may then be inaccessible or not function properly. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe's website.

If you do not wish to have your personal information used by the Company to promote our own or third parties' products or services, you can opt-out by checking the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data or at any other time by logging into the Website or App and adjusting your user preferences in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an e-mail stating your request. You may also change your marketing preferences or remove yourself from our mailing list by clicking on the “unsubscribe” hyperlink contained at the bottom of the emails we send to you.

If at any time you wish to stop receiving e-mail from us, you can always remove your name from our mailing list by sending an e-mail to Customerservice@drfuhrman.com stating that you wish to unsubscribe and indicating in the subject line of the e-mail "NO E-MAIL". Although we will promptly remove your name from our e-mail list upon receiving your request, it is possible that you may still receive e-mails from us that had been initiated prior to your name being removed from our list.

## Legal Basis for Processing European Individual’s Personal Data

The applicable legal basis for which we process your Personal Data includes:

### Based on your consent

In some cases, we may process your personal information based on your consent. If you choose to provide us with your consent, you may later withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us as described in the “contact us”.

### Compliance with applicable laws

In specific circumstances, we may process your personal information to comply with a relevant law/regulation or to fulfill our obligations under a contract to which you are subject. Where we process your personal information to meet our legal obligations, you will likely not be permitted to object to this processing activity, but you will usually have the right to access or review this information unless it would impede our legal obligations, for example, alerting you about product safeties in compliance with applicable food, daily supplement, drug, etc. related laws and regulations.

### Performance of a contract

We may process your personal data based on a contract you entered with us, e.g., a purchase order. Where we are processing to fulfill our contract obligations under a contract where you are a party, you might not be able to object to this processing, or if you do choose to opt-out or object to our processing, you voluntarily forfeit the relevant contractual obligations that you are owed.

### Our legitimate interest

We may process your personal information based on our legitimate interests in communicating with you and managing our interactions with you regarding our products and services, scientific research, and education opportunities. You have the right to object to such processing of your personal information. You can inform us your objection by contacting us as described in the “contact us” section below.

## Data Transfers

We may transfer the personal information we obtain about you to the United States and other countries, other than the country in which the information originally was collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. To the extent required by applicable law, when we transfer your personal information to the United States, we will take measures to protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

By submitting personal information to us, you understand that this information will be transferred to DrFuhrman.com in the United States. If you do not want your personal information transferred to the United States, please do not submit any information to us or otherwise use our products or services.

## Changes to Privacy Policy

DrFuhrman.com may, in its sole discretion, change this Privacy Policy from time to time without prior notice. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by changing the "Last Updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If you use this Website or App after a change to this Privacy Policy is posted, you will be bound by such change. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis. If you object to any of the terms in our revised Privacy Policy, you have the right to cease using the services provided on this Website or App. If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practice in general, please contact us as described in the “contact us” section below.

## European Privacy Rights

### Rights to update and access your information

You have the right to update your personal information at any time by logging into your online account or contacting us as described in the “contact us” section below. You have the right to request a report concerning what personal information we collected and whether we shared any of your personal information with a third party for what purpose thereof. To request such a report please contact us as described in the “contact us” section below.

### Right to limit the use and disclosure of personal information

You have the right to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information. As previously disclosed, you may opt-out from receiving promotional emails from us regarding new features, services and special offers when registering for an account by unchecking the box that asks whether you would like to receive email updates. You may unsubscribe from receiving promotional emails of certain types (or a company-wide unsubscribe) at any time by logging into your online account or contact us as described in the “contact us” section below.

### Complaint

If you have any complaint about our privacy practice, please send your complaint directly to us as described in the “contact us” section below. We will endorse good faith effort to resolve your concerns to your satisfaction.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions, feel free to contact us by one of the following methods:

Phone:  
1-800-474-WELL (9355)

Electronic:  
Contact Us Form

Physical Address:  
4 Walter E. Foran Blvd., Suite 408  
Flemington, NJ 08822
